CHANGJIAN LI

Room Y001, 2004 route des lucioles BP 93, FR-06902, Sophia Antipolis, France $(+86)18769782736/(+33)0781960521 \diamond$ chjili2011@gmail.com

RESEARCH INTEREST

I have a great passion for working on Graphics and Vision problems with a broad range of research interests including sketch-based shape modeling, 3D reconstruction, 3D vision, medical image processing, deep learning and geometry processing.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Starting Researcher GraphDeco Group, Inria Sophia-Antipolis, France	Oct. 2021 - present
Postdoctoral Research Associate Smart Geometry Processing Group, University College London, UK Hosted by Prof. Niloy Mitra	Oct. 2019 - Sep. 2021
Teaching Assistant Department Computer Science, University College London, UK	Oct. 2019 - Sep. 2021
Teaching Assistant Department Computer Science, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong	Aug. 2014 - Sep. 2019
EDUCATION	
The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong Ph.D., Department of Computer Science Supervisor: Prof. Wenping Wang	Aug. 2014 - Sep. 2019
Shandong University, Jinan BEng, Software Engineering Software College	Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

^{*}corresponding author

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Changjian Li, Hao Pan, Adrien Bousseau, Niloy Mitra. 2020. Sketch2CAD: Sequential CAD Modeling by Sketching in Context. ACM Trans. Graph., 39(6), 2020, proceedings of SIGGRAPH Asia, 2020.

Zhiming Cui, Bojun Zhang, Chunfeng Lian, **Changjian Li***, Lei Yang, Min Zhu*, Wenping Wang, Dinggang Shen*. 2021. *Hierarchical Morphology-Guided Tooth Instance Segmentation from CBCT Images*. Information Processing in Medical Imaging (IPMI) 2021. (Oral Presentation)

Cheng Lin, **Changjian Li***, Yuan Liu, Nenglun Chen, Yi-King Choi, Wenping Wang*. 2021. *Point2Skeleton: Learning Skeletal Representations from Point Clouds*. IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021. (Oral Presentation, Best Paper Nomination)

Changjian Li, Hao Pan, Yang Liu, Xin Tong, Alla Sheffer, Wenping Wang. 2018. Robust Flow-Guided Neural Prediction for Sketch-Based Freeform Surface Modeling. ACM Trans. Graph., 37(6), 2018, proceedings of SIGGRAPH Asia 2018.

Changjian Li, Hao Pan, Yang Liu, Xin Tong, Alla Sheffer, Wenping Wang. 2017. *BendSketch: Modeling Freeform Surfaces Through 2D Sketching*. ACM Trans. Graph., 36(4), 2017, proceedings of SIGGRAPH 2017.

FULL PUBLICATION LIST

*corresponding author

3D Shape Modeling

Changjian Li, Hao Pan, Adrien Bousseau, Niloy Mitra. 2020. Sketch2CAD: Sequential CAD Modeling by Sketching in Context. ACM Trans. Graph., 39(6), 2020, proceedings of SIGGRAPH Asia, 2020.

Changjian Li, Hao Pan, Yang Liu, Xin Tong, Alla Sheffer, Wenping Wang. 2018. Robust Flow-Guided Neural Prediction for Sketch-Based Freeform Surface Modeling. ACM Trans. Graph., 37(6), 2018, proceedings of SIGGRAPH Asia 2018.

Changjian Li, Hao Pan, Yang Liu, Xin Tong, Alla Sheffer, Wenping Wang. 2017. *BendSketch: Modeling Freeform Surfaces Through 2D Sketching*. ACM Trans. Graph., 36(4), 2017, proceedings of SIGGRAPH 2017.

Hao Pan, Yang Liu, Alla Sheffer, Nicholas Vining, **Changjian Li**, Wenping Wang. 2015. Flow Aligned Surfacing of Curve Networks. ACM Trans. Graph., 36(4), 2015, proceedings of SIGGRAPH 2015.

3D Shape Analysis

Cheng Lin, **Changjian Li***, Yuan Liu, Nenglun Chen, Yi-King Choi, Wenping Wang*. 2021. *Point2Skeleton: Learning Skeletal Representations from Point Clouds*. IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021. (Oral Presentation, Best Paper Nomination)

Cheng Lin, Lingjie Liu, **Changjian Li**, Leif Kobbelt, Bin Wang, Shiqing Xin, Wenping Wang. 2020. SEG-MAT: 3D Shape Segmentation Using Medial Axis Transform. IEEE Visualization and Computer Graphics (TVCG), 2020).

Medical Image Processing

Zhiming Cui, **Changjian Li**, Lei Yang, Chunfeng Lian, Feng Shi, Wenping Wang, Dijia Wu, Dinggang Shen. 2021. *VertNet: Accurate Vertebra Localization and Identification Network from CT Images*. International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2021.

Zhiming Cui, **Changjian Li**, Zhixu Du, Nenglun Chen, Guodong Wei, Runnan Chen, Lei Yang, Dinggang Shen, Wenping Wang. 2021. Structure-Driven Unsupervised Domain Adaptation for Cross-Modality Cardiac Segmentation. IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging (TMI), 2021.

Zhiming Cui, Bojun Zhang, Chunfeng Lian, **Changjian Li***, Lei Yang, Min Zhu*, Wenping Wang, Dinggang Shen*. 2021. *Hierarchical Morphology-Guided Tooth Instance Segmentation from CBCT Images*. Information Processing in Medical Imaging (IPMI) 2021. (Oral Presentation)

Zhiming Cui, **Changjian Li**, Nenglun Chen, Guodong Wei, Runnan Chen, Yuanfeng Zhou, Dinggang Shen*, Wenping Wang*. 2021. TSegNet: an Efficient and Accurate Tooth Segmentation Network

on 3D Dental Model. Medical Image Analysis (MIA), 2021.

Zhiming Cui, **Changjian Li**, Wenping Wang. 2019. ToothNet: Automatic Tooth Instance Segmentation and Identification from Cone Beam CT Images. IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019.

3D Reconstruction

Yushiang Wong, **Changjian Li**, Matthias Niessner, Niloy Mitra. 2021. RigidFusion: RGB-D Scene Reconstruction with Rigidly-moving Objects. Eurographics (EG), 2021.

Cheng Lin, Changjian Li, Wenping Wang. 2019. Floorplan-Jigsaw: Jointly Estimating Scene Layout and Aligning Partial Scans. International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2019.

3D Texture Synthesis

Hui Zhang, Lei Yang, Changjian Li, Bojian Wu, Wenping Wang. 2021. ScaffoldGAN: Synthesis of Scaffold Materials based on Generative Adversarial Networks. Computer-Aided Design (CAD), 2021.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Intern Feb. 2016 - Aug. 2018

Microsoft Research Asia, Beijing

 $Multiple\ Times$

- Mentor: Dr. Hao Pan, and Dr. Xin Tong

Research Assistant Feb. 2014 - Jun. 2014

The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

- Supervisor: Prof. Wenping Wang

- Bachelor Thesis: Sketch-based Modeling: An Intuitive Modeling Interface.

INVITED TALKS

Stanford Human-Computer Interaction Group, Stanford Jan. 2021

Sketch2CAD: Sequential CAD Modeling by Sketching in Context.

AI Lab, Autodesk Jan. 2021

Sketch2CAD: Sequential CAD Modeling by Sketching in Context.

Software College, Shandong University, Jinan Oct. 2019

Sketch-based Freeform Surface Modeling.

iDDA, The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen Jul. 2019

SketchAShape: Sketch-based Freeform Surface Modeling.

IRC Lab, Shandong University

Mar. 2019

Robust Flow-Guided Neural Prediction for Sketch-Based Freeform Surface Modeling. Automatic Tooth Instance Segmentation and Identification from CBCT Images.

DGP Lab, University of Toronto Sept. 2018

BendSketch: Modeling Freeform Surfaces Through 2D Sketching.

GAMES: Graphics And Mixed Environment Seminar, China	Nov. 2018
Robust Flow-Guided Neural Prediction for Sketch-Rased Freeform Surface Modeling	

IN THE PRESS

CCTV News Report. World Artificial Intelligence Conference (WAIC) - SketchCNN.	201
Computer Vision News, The magazine of the algorithm community. ICCV Daily 2019 Floorplan-Jigsaw.	201
IEEE Computer Society.	201
Poster Sessions Provoke Deep Discussions at the 2019 Conference on CVPR - ToothNe	et.
SIGGRAPH Asia Technical Paper Press Releases. SketchCNN: Making it Easier To Transform FreeForm 2D Sketching Into 3D Models.	201
Seamless, Virtual Reality.	201
A new method using CNN to model 3D surface from handwritten 2D sketch.	
TEACHING ASSISTANT	
COMP0119 - Acquisition and Processig of 3D Geometry. UCL, CS.	2020-2021, S
COMP2396 - Object Oriented Programming and Java. HKU, CS.	2017-2018, \$
ENGG1111 - Computer Programming and Applications. HKU, CS.	2016-2017, \$
COMP7507 - Visualization and Visual Analytics. HKU, CS.	2015-2016, 3
ENGG1111 - Computer Programming and Applications. HKU, CS.	2014-2015, \$
REVIEWER SERVICE	
ACM SIGGRAPH	202
ACM SIGGRAPH Asia	2019, 202
Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)	202
IEEE Transactions on Visualization & Computer Graphics (TVCG)	2020, 202
Eurographics (EG)	20:
Computer Graphics Forum (CGF) Journal of Computer Science and Technology (JCST)	20: 20:
Pacific Graphics (PG)	201
Eurographics Symposium on Geometry Processing (SGP)	20.
International Conference on Computer-Aided Design and Graphics (CAD&CG)	201
Sensors	202
ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (UIST)	202
AWARDS AND PRIZES	
YS & Christabel Lung PG Scholarship (HKU).	201
President's Scholarship of Shandong University (top 0.5 %, highest student honor).	201
Google Excellent Student Scholarship (top 0.5%).	201
Nation Scholarship of China (top 2%, twice).	2011, 201
Excellent Student of Shandong Province (top 0.05 %).	201
Bronze Medal - The ACM/ICPC Asia Regional Contest, Changchun Site.	201

Language: Mandarin(native), English(fluent), Cantonese(basic)

Hobby: Basketball, Swimming, Cooking, Badminton, Hiking, Movie